New York Society for Medical History Records
New York Society for Medical History Records
1938-1955
New York Society for Medical History
.7 linear feet; 2 boxes
Mss.arc
New York Academy of Medicine Library. Rare Book Room.
Historical Note
The New York Society for Medical History was founded in 1939, the year its forerunner, the Innominate Club, disbanded. While the Innominate Club was a small, private group, the New York Society for Medical History was open to anyone, medically trained or not, interested in the history of medicine. Many prominent figures in the field were officers and members. Until 1952, the Society was a constituent member of the American Association of the History of Medicine. Scholarship was at the forefront of the organization, which organized presentations of papers and programs on the history of medicine.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of correspondence, constitution and by-laws, minutes, programs, member lists, photographs, and other materials. The majority of the collection pertains to the New York Society for Medical History, but Innominate Club materials can be found in a folder of correspondence, as well as bound with the first volume of New York Society for Medical History documents.
Arrangement of Collection
Records bound chronologically into 6 volumes, with loose items arranged in folders.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of The New York Academy of Medicine Library. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Medicine -- New York (State) -- New York -- Societies, etc.; Medicine -- History -- Societies, etc.; New York Society for Medical History.; Innominate Club.; Bett, Walter Reginald, 1903-; Castiglioni, Arturo, 1874-1953.; Galdston, Iago, 1895-; Hartung, Edward F.; Robinson, Victor, 1886-1947.; Zilboorg, Gregory, 1890-1959.; Sigerist, Henry E. (Henry Ernest), 1891-1957.
Container List
  - Records, July 1938 to June 1940. (Box 1)
  - Records, July 1940 to June 1941.; This volume is missing. (Box 1)
  - Records, July 1941 to June 1942. (Box 1)
  - Records, July 1942 to June 1943. (Box 1)
  - Records, July 1943 to June 1944. (Box 1)
  - Records, 1943 - 1955. (Box 2)
  - Innominate Club Correspondence, 1939. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Constitution and By-laws. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Documents, undated; 1939-1947. (Box 2, Folder 3)
Provenance
Donated by Mrs. Walter R. Bett in 1968.